<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>
            Oovi-kat
        </name>
        <update version="0.0.4">
            <file name="race-oovikat.xml"
                url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Yurmin/dnd-lol-content/master/league-of-legends-handbook/lol-race-oovikat.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <!-- Note: This race comes from https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Oovi-Kat_(5e_Race), as such it's
    not an original part of the LOLHB mentioned in other files in this repository -->
    <element name="Oovi-kat" type="Race" source="dandwiki" id="ID_ORKIDIAN_LOLHB_RACE_OOVIKAT">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">
                "The Oovi-Kat are gone. Neeko must build her own tribe, now."
            </p>
            <h4>
                Physical Description
            </h4>
            <p>
                The Oovi-Kat are a tribe of essentially chameleon like humans, they have smooth
                skin, up to half their limbs, as a greenish scaly skin replaces the skin at their
                shoulders, neck, hands and feet. Each Oovi-Kat has their own special colors that
                signify their own personality, often showing at the tips of their fingers and toes,
                making different patterns and bright colors along their tails though green is always
                present on their body, possibly to help with camouflage in the deep forest.
            </p>
            <h4>
                History
            </h4>
            <p>
                Not much is know of about the Oovi-Kat, other than that they lived in deep forests,
                away from civilization. Some, however, have chosen to leave the confines of their
                forests and explore the world. Their origins are known only by elder oovi-kats, and
                are usually kept from the newer generations. Either in regret, or in fear.
            </p>
            <h4>
                Society
            </h4>
            <p>
                The Oovi-Kat were peaceful beings of unrivaled potential. Their harmonious society
                blended seamlessly with the spirit realm, so that their sho’ma — their spiritual
                essence — could intermingle with other beings through mere proximity, and even help
                them mimic other physical forms. No secrets existed between the Oovi-Kat.
            </p>
            <h4>
                Oovi-Kat Names
            </h4>
            <p>
                Vastayan names are typically drawn from the vastayan language, but some might be
                based in Ionian script. Names are given at birth, by parents or by tribe elders,
                depending on clan traditions.
            </p>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">
                    Male Names:
                </span> Yann, Muute, Rekon. <br />
                <span
                    class="feature">
                    Female Names:
                </span> Neeko, Ginna, Fainn. </p>
            <h4>
                Oovi-Kat Traits
            </h4>
            <p>
                The Oovi-Kat are a race known for their individuality... and their disguises. Your
                Oovi-Kat character has the following traits:
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong>
                    <em>
                        Ability Score Increase.
                    </em>
                </strong>
                Your Wisdom score increases by 2 and your Charisma score increases by 1. </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong>
                    <em>
                        Age.
                    </em>
                </strong>
                A member of the Oovi-Kat can be 400 year before their the equivalent of a 20-year
                old human mentally. There is no known end to the lifespan of one, as most were
                killed instead of actually dying from age. </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong>
                    <em>
                        Alignment.
                    </em>
                </strong>
                Most Oovi-Kats were neutral, given how they separated themselves from the outside
                world. Despite this, those who chose to abandon their native forests often built
                their own ideas and were thus of different alignments.</p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong>
                    <em>
                        Size.
                    </em>
                </strong>
                Oovi-Kat vary widely in height and build, from barely 5 feet to well over 6 feet
                tall. Your tail can be 4 to 6 feet long. Your size is Medium. </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong>
                    <em>
                        Speed.
                    </em>
                </strong>
                Your base walking speed is 30 feet. You also have a Climbing speed of 25. </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong>
                    <em>
                        Darkvision.
                    </em>
                </strong>
                The Oovi-Kat are able to sense their surroundings, even in the darkest forests they
                came from. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright
                light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. Like most races, you can't designate
                color, as it only shows shades of grey. But, unlike most races, you see living
                things in certain colors, depending on how you Identify them as. Green for friends,
                blue for family members, red for dangererous creatures, and purple for unknown ones.
                You also discern preys and food sources in orange. </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong>
                    <em>
                        Shapeshifting.
                    </em>
                </strong>
                The Oovi-Kat are known for there chameleon-like camouflage, and there ability to
                change into people. As a action, A Oovi-Kat can turn into another humanoid they have
                seen before. They have advantage on using the <strong>Deception</strong> skill while
                using this form. If you take damage, you need to make a concentration check to stay
                in that form, as it takes a great deal of concentration to stay in another form. You
                automatically revert to your normal self if you become incapacitated. </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong>
                    <em>
                        Chameleon Stride.
                    </em>
                </strong>
                The Oovi-Kat are skilled at not being seen, if they don't want to be. You gain
                proficiency in the Stealth skill. </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong>
                    <em>
                        Long Tail.
                    </em>
                </strong>
                The Oovi-Kat have long tails. You can make a unarmed attack with your tail as a
                normal action, or make a Grapple check with your tail. If you hit, you deal 1d4
                Bludgeoning. This uses Dexterity </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong>
                    <em>
                        Empathetic link.
                    </em>
                </strong>
                The Oovi-Kat have only lived with themselves, and their link to the ethereal plane
                has allowed them to sense the emotions of other beings more that most people, as
                emotion is what links all sentient beings together, and is used by the Oovi-Kat to
                tell which person is which since they are a tribe of shape-shifters. You gain
                proficiency in the Insight skill. </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <strong>
                    <em>
                        Languages
                    </em>
                </strong>
                You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan. </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <setters>
            <set name="names-format">
                {{name}}
            </set>
            <set name="height" modifier="2d6">
                5'3"
            </set>
            <set name="weight" modifier="1d6">
                50 lb
            </set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="innate speed:climb" value="25" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="wisdom" value="2"/>
            <stat name="charisma" value="1"/>
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ORKIDIAN_LOLHB_RACIAL_TRAIT_OOVIKAT_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ORKIDIAN_LOLHB_RACIAL_TRAIT_SHAPESHIFTING" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ORKIDIAN_LOLHB_RACIAL_TRAIT_CHAMELEON_STRIDE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ORKIDIAN_LOLHB_RACIAL_TRAIT_LONG_TAIL" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_ORKIDIAN_LOLHB_RACIAL_TRAIT_EMPATHETIC_LINK" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Darkvision" type="Racial Trait" source="League of Legends Handbook"
        id="ID_ORKIDIAN_LOLHB_RACIAL_TRAIT_OOVIKAT_DARKVISION">
        <description>
            The Oovi-Kat are able to sense their surroundings, even in the darkest forests they
            came from. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright
            light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. Like most races, you can't designate
            color, as it only shows shades of grey. But, unlike most races, you see living
            things in certain colors, depending on how you Identify them as. Green for friends,
            blue for family members, red for dangererous creatures, and purple for unknown ones.
            You also discern preys and food sources in orange. </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                The Oovi-Kat are able to sense their surroundings, even in the darkest forests they
                came from. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright
                light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. Like most races, you can't designate
                color, as it only shows shades of grey. But, unlike most races, you see living
                things in certain colors, depending on how you Identify them as. Green for friends,
                blue for family members, red for dangererous creatures, and purple for unknown ones.
                You also discern preys and food sources in orange. </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Shapeshifting" type="Racial Trait" source="League of Legends Handbook"
        id="ID_ORKIDIAN_LOLHB_RACIAL_TRAIT_SHAPESHIFTING">
        <description> The Oovi-Kat are known for there chameleon-like camouflage, and there ability
            to change into people. As a action, A Oovi-Kat can turn into another humanoid they have
            seen before. They have advantage on using the <strong>Deception</strong> skill while
            using this form. If you take damage, you need to make a concentration check to stay in
            that form, as it takes a great deal of concentration to stay in another form. You
            automatically revert to your normal self if you become incapacitated. </description>
        <sheet>
            <description> The Oovi-Kat are known for there chameleon-like camouflage, and there
                ability to change into people. As a action, A Oovi-Kat can turn into another
                humanoid they have seen before. They have advantage on using the <strong>Deception</strong>
                skill while using this form. If you take damage, you need to make a concentration
                check to stay in that form, as it takes a great deal of concentration to stay in
                another form. You automatically revert to your normal self if you become
                incapacitated. </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ALTER_SELF" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Chameleon Stride" type="Racial Trait" source="League of Legends Handbook"
        id="ID_ORKIDIAN_LOLHB_RACIAL_TRAIT_CHAMELEON_STRIDE">
        <description>
            The Oovi-Kat are skilled at not being
            seen, if they don't want to be. You gain proficiency in the Stealth skill. </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                The Oovi-Kat are skilled at not being
                seen, if they don't want to be. You gain proficiency in the Stealth skill. </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Long Tail" type="Racial Trait" source="League of Legends Handbook"
        id="ID_ORKIDIAN_LOLHB_RACIAL_TRAIT_LONG_TAIL">
        <description>
            The Oovi-Kat have long
            tails. You can make a unarmed attack with your tail as a normal action, or make a
            Grapple
            check with your tail. If you hit, you deal 1d4 Bludgeoning. This uses Dexterity </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description> You make an unarmed attack or try to grapple an enemy with your tail. If
                you hit with it you deal 1d4+{{dexterity:modifier}} bludgeoning damage and can use
                dexterity as for the attack roll. Also, if you try to grapple an enemy with your
                tail, you can use <em>Acrobatics</em> instead of <em>Athletics</em> for your check. </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Empathetic link" type="Racial Trait" source="League of Legends Handbook"
        id="ID_ORKIDIAN_LOLHB_RACIAL_TRAIT_EMPATHETIC_LINK">
        <description>
            The Oovi-Kat have
            only lived with themselves, and their link to the ethereal plane has allowed them to
            sense
            the emotions of other beings more that most people, as emotion is what links all
            sentient
            beings together, and is used by the Oovi-Kat to tell which person is which since they
            are a
            tribe of shape-shifters. You gain proficiency in the Insight skill. </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>
                The Oovi-Kat have
                only lived with themselves, and their link to the ethereal plane has allowed them to
                sense
                the emotions of other beings more that most people, as emotion is what links all
                sentient
                beings together, and is used by the Oovi-Kat to tell which person is which since
                they
                are a
                tribe of shape-shifters. You gain proficiency in the Insight skill. </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>